Sonal Sharma

Automation Test Engineer

As a B.Tech- CSE graduate with 3.8+ years of work experience in the Insurance and Logistics domain as Automation and Manual Testing, knowing object-oriented programming, designing test cases, and creating/running automation scripts seek to join the growing organization. I can master new technologies and successfully work in team and self-directed settings.



sonalssharma06@gmail.com



08650125283



Pune, India



in linkedin.com/in/sonal-sharma-1a81521aa

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Analyst ClickPost

03/2023 - 12/2024

Pune

Multi-carrier logistics management and intelligence platform helping 250+ big and small enterprises with their logistics operations.

- Hands-on Experience in writing Test Cases, developing and maintaining Test scripts, analyzing the results of scripts, and interacting with developers in fixing the errors.
- Extensive knowledge in **Automation script creation** using Selenium webDriver with java and TestNG. Hands-on experience with the Page Object Model framework.
- E2E API testing using Postman and running SQL query for database validation
- Hands on Experience in Web based testing including GUI Testing, Regression Testing, Integration Testing, White Box Testing, BlackBox Testing and Functional Testing.
- Working as an independent QA for handling/managing quality testing across the entire API PODs
- Working in a logistic domain with direct B2B and B2C customers interaction

Programmer Analyst Cognizant

03/2021 - 01/2023

Pune

Achievements/Tasks

- Given full ownership of the BOP LOB within one year for determining optimal direction for the project on a statergic
- Expertise in TestNG annotations, Grouping and Parallel execution.
- Responsible for End to End Automation Script work (with over 100+ Test cases) using CITS (Cognizant Intelligent Test Scripter) and TAC (Test Automation center).
- Perform E2E testing on Chubb Project on DuckCreek and Marketplace applications in BOP, UMB, Auto and Cyber LOBs for Insurance domain and performed E2E Regression Testing for various sprint releases.
- Digital testing with the help of API testing in postman. Hands on experience in Client WIP and Soap UI (general flow).
- Delivering training sessions for 20+ new new joiniees and demonstrating progress presentation in weekly client meet.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Technology (Computer Science) DIT University

2017 - 2021 Dehradun

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Outstanding Delivery Contribution

Got appreciated in identifying two critical testing defects, one of which was a Compliance issue for the sprint release. My efforts were greatly appreciated by the Client as well.

Leadership Appreciation

Got recognized for hosting and organizing Friday Fun Session in the organization

CERTIFICATES

SelectorsHub Certification Program

Completed selecter hub certification program on identifying the different locators in selenium

Automated Web Testing with Selenium

Completed software testing certification course organized by Cognizant

LANGUAGES

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Content Creation

Voulunteering Activities

Hindi

Public Speaking

Yoga/Fitness